# FRANCESCA FRANZ

### CONTACTS

• Castelfranco Veneto, TV

francesca.franz.33@gmail.com

in LinkedIn Profile

Portfolio

+39 347 6612225

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

●●●● Italian (Native)

•••• English (C2)

••• French (C1)

●●●● Japanese (N2)

#### TOOLS

•••• Office, iWork, G-Suite

Figma, Miro, VSCode, Github, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

•••• Windows, MacOS, Linux

•••• HTML5, CSS

### CERTIFICATIONS

UX/UI Design - Fastweb Digital Academy (october 2023)

Digital Skills: User Experience - Accenture (march 2022)

### VOLUNTEERING

Collaborator and language expert - Objectif Sciences International (2020-)

Translation and proofreading (vacances-scientifiques.com)

Member- ESN Venezia and Buddy Program (2015 - 2017)

Organisation of activities and events; support for international students.

Tour guide - Torre civica di Castelfranco Veneto (2015 - 2016)

### HOBBIES

Dance for 9 years; travel; photography; bullet journaling.

I hereby consent to the processing of my personal data contained in this CV in accordance with Article 6.1(a) of the GDPR, i.e. Regulation (EU) 2016/679.

My studies in Oriental languages, and my experiences in Japan and France, have taught me the importance of dialogue and engaging with others, leading me to develop a particular sensitivity in considering different viewpoints, often discovering new and surprising perspectives. These experiences, combined with my years of dancing, have also helped me appreciate the importance of personal expression and adaptability.

All of this has inspired me to finally pursue a Master's in UX/UI Design, where I built and honed my skills in wireframing, prototyping, and user research. My portfolio includes some practical projects I have completed during my studies.

I am excited to seek opportunities in dynamic and creative companies where I can tackle varied challenges and contribute to creating intuitive and meaningful user experiences.

# **EDUCATION**

# Master in UX-UI Design

Start2Impact University | april 2022 - july 2024

- Copywriting; Graphic Design; HTML and CSS; Discovery, Accessibility, Wireframing, User Interface, User Testing.
- Creation of practical projects for every subject covered during the course.
- Attention to details, precision and autonomous management of projects.

Master in Global Marketing, Communication and Made in Italy Centro Studi Comunicare Impresa | october 2019 - april 2021

Master's Degree in Languages, economies and institutions of Asia and North Africa, curriculum Japan (LM38)

Ca' Foscari University of Venice | september 2016 - 19 march 2019

### Erasmus +

Université Paris Diderot et INALCO | september 2017 - june 2018

Degree in Languages, cultures and societies of Asia and North Africa, curriculum Japan

Ca' Foscari University of Venice | september 2012 - july 2016

### Exchange student

University of Kouchi, Japan | april 2015 - june 2015

### EXPERIENCE

### Apprenticeship in a tax assistance centre

CAF MGS | august 2022 - december 2022

- Tax assistance center employee
- Problem solving skills, attention to detail and customer management.
- Interpreter for foreign clients (English and French).

## Translator

Fiverr | october 2020 - october 2021

- Self management of projects and customers.
- Translations from Japanese, French or English to Italian.

### Intern

Fondazione Benetton | july 2018 - august 2018

- Interpreter and linguistic and cultural mediator for Gallerie delle Prigioni.
- Front office and clients interaction and management.